# Laura Greenstreet



I am a PhD student at Cornell working with Dr. Carla Gomes to develop AI and optimization methods with sustainability applications, including mapping aquaculture with remote sensing and invasive species management. Previously, I worked with Dr. Claire Kremen to scale an analysis of functional connectivity to the global level and with Dr. Geoffrey Schiebinger to develop optimization methods for single-cell genomics.

#### EDUCATION -

2021 - Present Ph.D. Computer Science, Cornell University

Research areas: Deep Learning, Remote Sensing, Optimization

2020 B.Sc. Honours Computer Science, Mathematics Minor,

University of British Columbia

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- 2023 Greenstreet, L., A. Afanassiev, Y. Kijima, M. Heitz, S. Ichiguro, et al. DNA-GPS: A Theoretical Framework for Optics-Free Spatial Genomics and Synthesis of Current Methods. Cell Systems, 2023. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cels.2023.08.005
- Mirka, R., L. Greenstreet, M. Grimson, C.P. Gomes. A New Approach to Finding 2 x n Partially Spatially Balanced Latin Rectangles, CP, 2023.
- Brennan, A., R. Naidoo, **L. Greenstreet**, Z. Mehrabi, N. Ramankutty, C. Kremen. Functional Connectivity of the Worlds Protected Areas. Science, 2022. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abl8974
- Greenstreet, L., N.J.A. Harvey, V. Sanches Portella. Efficient and Optimal Fixed-Time Regret with Two Experts. ALT, 2022. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2203.07577
- Zhang, S., A. Afanassiev, **L. Greenstreet**, T. Matsumoto, G. Schiebinger. *Optimal transport analysis reveals trajectories in steady-state systems*. PLOS Computational Biology, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1009466
- Li, H., J. Ezike, A. Afanassiev, **L. Greenstreet**, et al. Single Cell Analysis Elucidates the Maturation of Human Stem and Progenitor Cell Function from Fetal through Adult Hematopoiesis. Blood, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood-2021-151090
- Shahan R., C. Hsu, T.M. Nolan, B.J. Cole, I.W. Taylor, **L. Greenstreet**, et al. A single cell Arabidopsis root atlas reveals developmental trajectories in wild type and cell identity mutants. Developmental Cell, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.devcel.2022.01.008
- Massri, A.J., L. Greenstreet, A. Afanassiev, A. Berrio Escobar, G.M. Wray, G. Schiebinger, D.R. McClay. Developmental Single-cell transcriptomics in the Lytechinus variegatus Sea Urchin Embryo. Development, 2020. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.198614

#### Workshops and Presentations –

- Greenstreet, L, J. Fan, F. Siqueira Pacheco, Y. Bai, M. Eichemberger Ummus, et al. *Detecting Aquaculture with Deep Learning in a Low-Data Setting*. SigKDD 2023 Fragile Earth Workshop.
- **Greenstreet, L**, and E. Lai. Developing a Data-Driven Electric Vehicle Strategy in Surrey, BC. SigKDD 2020 Social Impact Session.



| Awards —   |  |
|------------|--|
| 2022, 2023 | Graduate Teaching Award x3, Department of Computer Science, Cornell University                                   |
| 2020       | <b>Undergraduate Summer Research Award</b> , Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC) |
| 2019       | Data Science for Social Good Fellowship, UBC Data Science Institute  |
| 2018       | Stanley M Grant Scholarship in Mathematics, UBC Department of Mathematics  |

### Languages and Technologies -

3+ Years Experience: Python, Git, Linux

1-3 Years Experience: R, Julia, Matlab, Java, SQL

Libraries/Tools: Pytorch, scipy, Geopandas, cvxpy, sklearn, QGIS, Postgres, Gurobi, CPLEX

**Experience:** deep learning with geospatial data, contrastive learning, manifold learning, optimization including mixed integer programming and optimal transport, data processing for geospatial and single-cell sequencing data, SQL database development and integration

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE -

| 05/2023 - Present | Research Assistant, Computational Sustainability Lab, Department of Computer  |
|-------------------|---|
| 05/2022 - 08/2022 | Science, Cornell University   |
| 05/2020 - 08/2021 | Research Assistant, Schiebinger Lab, Department of Mathematics, University of |
|                   | British Columbia  |
| 09/2019 - 09/2020 | Research Assistant, WoRCS Lab, Institute for Resources, Environment, and Sus- |
|                   | tainability, University of British Columbia                                   |
| 05/2019 - 08/2019 | Fellow - Data Science for Social Good Program, University of British Columbia |
|                   | Data Science Institute  |

### Work Experience —

| 09/2022 - 05/2023   | <ul> <li>Head Teaching Assistant, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY</li> <li>CS 2700 - Excursions in Computational Sustainability</li> <li>CS 4700/4701 - Foundations/Practicum in Artificial Intelligence</li> </ul> |
|---|--|
| 09/2021 - 05/2022   | Teaching Assistant, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY CS 4220 - Numerical Analysis: Linear and Nonlinear Problems CS 3220 - Computational Mathematics for Computer Science  |
| 10/2021 - 11/2021<br>01/2019 - 05/2019<br>07/2015 - 08/2017 | Database Consultant, City of Surrey, Vancouver BC eTextbook Developer, University of British Columbia Library, Vancouver, BC Information Technology Coordinator, Tilth Alliance, Seattle, WA                       |

## COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT —

| 2023      | Organizer, NeurIPS Computational Sustainability Workshop                    |
|-----------|---|
| 2023      | Mentor, BURE Undergraduate Research Program, Cornell                        |
| 2023      | Volunteer TA, AI for Science Program, Cornell                               |
| 2020-2021 | Mentor, Data Science for Social Good Program, UBC Data Science Institute    |
| 2019      | Tutor, Emerging Indigenous Scholars Program, University of British Columbia |